A Guide to the Edward Lawrie Tatum papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA133
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Conferences; meetings; seminars, 1946-1975; 5
  - La Jolla, Calif. 26th symposium of the Society for Developmental Biology on control mechanisms in developmental processes June 19 Tatum "Nuclear and cytoplasmic control processes in the morphology of Neurospora", 1967 June 19-21 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    Tatum and Luck Published In: Locke, Michael, ed., Control mechanisms in developmental processes. New York, Academic Press, 1967. pp. 32-42.
  - New Jersey [Information from original folder] Outline of address "no title", 1967 October 31 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - NYC National Cystic Fibrosis Research Foundation / U.S. Public Health Service symposium on cystic fibrosis and related human and animal diseases, 1968 February 29-March 2 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    Tatum "Molecular engineering".
  - Cincinnati, Ohio University of Cincinnati College of Medicine 32nd Rachford symposium to dedicate Institute for developmental research, 1968 June 19 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    Tatum "Molecular biology and mental retardation research".
  - Aspen, Colorado 5th annual pathobiology conf Tatum "Gene action", 1968 August 4-13 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Dallas, National Science Teachers Assoc convention on horizons for the 70's, 1969 March 21-25 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    Tatum Damon lecturer "Science and citizen: horizons for the 70's.
    Published in THE SCIENCE TEACHER 36 (1969) 10-16.
  - Boston, Children's Hospital centennial celebration, 1969 April 18-19 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Tatum "Molecules, genes and child health".
  - St. Peter, Minn. Gustavus Adolphus Nobel conference, 1971 January 6-7 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    Includes handwritten note by Mrs. Rous on "Tribute" [Not listed in Tatum bibliograph].
    Tatum "Tribute to Peyton Rous".
  - Colorado Springs, Teaching Institute of the Assoc of the American Medical Colleges, 1971 December 3-7 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    Tatum "The role of the medical school in guiding the evolution of our understanding of human biology".
  - RU lecture-seminar series on science and the evolution of public policy Tatum member of advisory group for lecture series, 1971 October-1972 circa April (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Notre Dame, Ind. University of Notre Dame dedication of Galvin Life Science center Tatum "Dedication of Galvin Life Science Center", 1972 April 28 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Washington, DC American Society of Zoologists symposium on role of RNA in reproduction and development, 1972 December 28-30 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    Tatum "Nucleic acid induced genetic changes in Neurospora".
    Published: Mishra, N.C., Szabo, G. and Tatum E.L. In: Niu, Mann Chiang. The role of RNA reproduction and development. New York, American Elsevier, 1973. pp. 259-268.
  - Upton, L.I. Brookhaven symposium in biology, 1973 June 4-6 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    Paper presented by Wm. A. Scott "Biochemical genetics of morphogenesis in Neurospora".
    Published: Scott, W.A., Mishra, N.C. and Tatum, E.L. In: Brookhaven Symposia in Biology: #25: Basic mechanisms in plant morphogenesis, 1973. pp. 1-18.
  - Invitations declined, 1956-1975; 4 folders (Box 41)
    Primarily invitations to meetings; conferences; seminars declined.
    Includes some miscellaneous other invitations declined. Includes such places as: University of Pennsylvania, Stanford University School of Medicine, President, USA invitation at presentation of 1966 recipients of the National Medal of Science, NAS (COSUP) Committee on Science and Public Policy (membership in), American Cancer Society, Harvard University, Sigma Xi lectures at various institutions.
    - 1956-1961 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - 1962-1965 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - 1969-1975 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Records of reimbursements (expenses and honorariums), 1952-1975 (Box 42)
    Primarily check stubs; expense and travel vouchers for travel reimbursement and honorariums for consultations, editorial services and addresses.
    - 1952-1957 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - 1958-1960 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - 1961-1966 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - 1967-1975 (Box 42, Folder 4)
- Annual scientific reports and manuscript material, 1956-1975; 6
  Files consist of correspondence; various drafts of manuscripts with working material; galley proofs; reprints of published papers; referees comments; some laboratory notes; photographic prints of figures. [Some published manuscripts not listed in Tatum bibliography]. In chronological order by publication date. [See also under: Correspondence; Subject Files; and Meetings for additional manuscript material (some published)].
  - Annual Scientific Reports 1957-1975; lacks 1964-1968; (1962-1963 research report - no annual report published for this year) (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - E.L. Tatum and S.R. Gross Incorporation of carbon atoms 1 and 6 of glucose into protocatechuic acid by Neurospora J BIOL CHEM 219, 797-807, 1956 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - E.L. Tatum Review of published symposium "A symposium on the chemical basis of heredity" SCIENCE 126, 313-314, 1957 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - E.L. Tatum Nobel lecture A case history in biology research (as published in) SCIENCE 129, 1711-1715, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - E.L. Tatum Book review: Human biochemical genetics by H. Harris ARCH BIOCHEM BIOPHYS 90, 162, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    [Not listed in Tatum bibliography].
  - S. Tsuda and E.L. Tatum, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Intracellular crystalline ergosterol in Neurospora JBBC 11, 171-177.
  - Noël de Terra and E.L. Tatum, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Includes copy of R.L. Metzenberg ms "The localization of B-fructofuranosidase in Neurospora" with Tatum review.
    A relationship between cell wall structure and colonial growth in Neurospora crassa AMER J BOTANY 50, 669-677.
  - B. Mach, E. Reich and E.L. Tatum, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    Separation of the biosynthesis of the antibiotic polypeptide tyrocidine from protein biosynthesis PNAS 50, 175-181.
  - L. Garnjobst, J.F. Wilson and E.L. Tatum, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    Studies on a cytoplasmic character in Neurospora crassa JCB 26, 413-425.
  - E.G. Diacumakos, L. Garnjobst and E.L. Tatum, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    A cytoplasmic character in Neurospora crassa. The role of nuclei and mitochondria.
    JCB 26, 427-443.
  - P.R. Mahadevan and E.L. Tatum, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    Relationship of the major constituents of the Neurospora crassa cell wall to wild-type and colonial morphology (title change from original ms) J BACTERIOLOGY 90, 1073-1081.
  - E.L. Tatum Joshua Lederberg. (Prepared for), 1966 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    THE ENCYCLOPEDIA OF AMERICA [Not listed in Tatum bibliography].
  - E.L. Tatum, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Can genes be made to order?
    - MEDICAL WORLD NEWS Oct 28 issue, pp. 105, 108, 109, 112, 113
    - [Not listed in Tatum bibliography]
  - E.L. Tatum, "Molecular biology, nucleic acids and the future of medicine", 1966 1967 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    In PERSPECTIVES IN BIOLOGY AND MEDICINE 10 (1966) 19-32 (At 1966 May 26 Merck symposium) and in: Lyght, Charles E. ed., Reflections on research and the future of medicine. New York, McGraw-Hill, 1967. pp. 31-49 (slight variation).
    Includes numerous items on 1966 May Merck symposium. Also includes news release and transcript of 1966 Sept WNBC television program "The future of medicine" Tatum participates in [See also box no. 20 Subject Files: Merck, Sharp and Dohme].
  - B. Crocken and E.L. Tatum, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    Sorbose transport in Neurospora crassa.
    BB ACTA 135, 100-105.
  - S. Brody and E.L. Tatum, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    Phosphoglucomutase mutants and morphological changes in Neurospora crassa.
    PNAS 58, 923-930.
  - L. Garnjobst and E.L. Tatum, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    Includes correspondence on Garnjobst and Tatum "crisp paper "New crisp genes and crisp modifiers in Neurospora". Published in 1970. [Lacks reprint in bound volume].
    GENETICS 57, 579-604.
    A survey of new morphological mutants in Neurospora crassa.
  - M.P. Morgan, L. Garnjobst and E.L. Tatum, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    Linkage relationship of new morphological mutants in linkage group V of Neurospora crassa.
    GENETICS 57, 605-615.
  - B. Crocken and E.L. Tatum, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    The effect of sorbose on metabolism and morphology of Neurospora BB ACTA 156, 1-8.
  - P.R. Mahadevan and E.L. Tatum, 1967
    Localization of structural polymers in the cell wall of Neurospora crassa J CELL BIOL 35, 295-302. In 3 folders:.
    - Corres; various drafts of ms; printer's and galley proofs with figures (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Photographic prints of figures (multiple copies) (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Retakes of P.R. [Mahadevan] #11,13 by D.D. Luck on 5/17/67 [Information from original folder] Possibly used (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - E.L. Tatum. Preface, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    In: Leonard Engle, THE NEW GENETICS. Doubleday, Garden City, New York, 1967. pp. 220.
  - W.A. Scott and E.L. Tatum, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase and Neurospora morphology.
    PNAS 66, 515-522.
  - N.C. Mishra and E.L. Tatum, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    Phosphoglucomutase mutants of Neurospora sitophila and their relation to morphology.
    PNAS 66, 638-645.
  - L. Garnjobst and E.L. Tatum, 1970; 2 folders (Box 45)
    New crisp genes and crisp-modifiers in Neurospora crassa. GENETICS 66, 281-290.
    - Corres; reviewers' comments; various drafts of ms and some working material (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Working material kept in order found (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - N.C. Mishra and E.L. Tatum, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    Effect of L-sorbose on polysaccharide synthetases of Neurospora crassa.
    PNAS 69, 313-317.
  - E.G. Diacumakos and E.L. Tatum, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    Fusion of mammalian somatic cells by microsurgery.
    PNAS 69, 2959-2962.
  - C.R. Wrathall and E.L. Tatum, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    The peptides of the hyphal wall of Neurospora crassa.
    J GEN MICROBIOLOGY 78, 139-153.
  - N.C. Mishra and E.L. Tatum, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    Non-Mendelian inheritance of DNA-induced inositol independence in Neurospora.
    PNAS 70, 3875-3879.
  - N.C. Mishra and E.L. Tatum, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    Induction by RNA of inositol independence in Neurospora crassa.
    PNAS 72, 642-655.
- Laboratory notes, 1937-1975; 7
  Files consist of notes (earliest notes in spiral notebooks); experimental data and calculations; graphs; various stock culture lists; keys; photographic prints. Some notes indexed and pages hand-numbered. Some by others.
  Kept in order found. In approximate chronological order.
  - Eye color hormones, 1937-1939; In 3 spiral notebooks (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - #1, 1937-1938
    - #2, 1938-1939
    - #3, 1939
  - Eye pigments. 1 spiral notebook, 1939 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - 3 spiral notebooks (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Starvation and nutrition - Book II, 1939 May (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Nutrition - Factor II and I, III - Book III, 1939 November-1940 September (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Includes reprint of Tatum "Nutritional requirements of Drosophila melangaster. PNAS 25 (1939) 490-497. [Lacks reprint in bound volume].
    - Drosophila nutrition - Book IV, 1940 October 16 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Sterile feeding I, [Year?] [J. Lederberg's note "probably 1939-1940" - on folder] Dec, January-May; 1 spiral notebook (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - 3 spiral notebooks (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - V + Hormone - Chemistry - Book #4, 1940 January 22
    - Chemistry - V + Bacterial - Book #5, 1940 May 2
    - Hormones - Book #6, 1941 Jan
  - Toxin (1 spiral notebook), 1940-1941 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - In 2 spiral notebooks, 1942-1943 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    Neurospora W-1.
    Neurospora W-II W experiments.
  - Neurospora notebooks, 1941 March-1942 March; 4 spiral notebooks (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Neurospora I, 1941 March
      Includes N-index and on [Oct 11, 1977 Joshua Lederberg examined the E.L. Tatum laboratory notebooks. Dr. Lederberg comments that this notebook is the most significant one on Neurospora. This records the initial work done on Neurospora.].
    - Neurospora II, 1941 October
    - Neurospora III pab, isol-val, miscellaneous, 1941 December
    - Neurospora IV pab and misc, 1942 March
  - [Joshua Lederberg further comments on Box 46 of Laboratory notes. Handwritten by J. Lederberg. Photocopy with encl]. [11/14/1982 E L T With the exception of Neurospora I (Mar 194 which dates the inception of Neurospora work (examined by me 11/77) there is not much than can be deciphered from these notebooks. The Drosophila books are mostly extraction/fractionation schemes for pigments; precursors (?), etc. I do not know what "toxin" is about, cf copies of a few pages copied out, encl. " Signed J. Lederberg] (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - [Neurospora notebooks continued in Box 47] (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Neurospora notebooks, 1942 September-1946 April; In 6 spiral notebooks (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Neurospora V Tryptophane 10575, 1942 September; 1 item
    - Neurospora VI purples, B6 curves, coli-u.v. biotin-bacteria, 1943 March; 11 items
    - Neurospora VII Tryptophane, 1943 April; 2 items
    - Neurospora VIII Tryptophane [Neurospora IX and X lacking], 1943 October; 3 items
    - Neurospora XI B1-B6, 1945 February; 3 items
    - Neurospora XII Histidine and miscellaneous NÂ¹âµ glycine etc., 1946 April
  - Neurospora notebooks, 1946 October-1948 February; In 4 spiral notebooks (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Neurospora XIII Y6994 and Y7655, 1948 February; 2 items
    - Neurospora XIV NÂ¹âµ tryptophane, histidine 4 & Y 249, 1946 October
    - Neurospora XV 6994 enrichment, detect, 1946 October; 11 items
    - Neurospora XVI Coli 5-recombination and transformation - detection, etc. techniques, 1947 October
  - Neurospora, 1946-1950; In 2 spiral notebooks (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Neurospora - Chemically induced mutations, 1947 February-1947 March; 1 item
    - Chemically induced mutations, 1947 April-1950 September; 2 items
  - Neurospora isolates. In 2 spiral notebooks, 1946 January-1948 April (Box 47, Folder 4)
    Includes: Master books 5 and 6.
  - 2 spiral notebooks, 1945-1946 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Biotin - Bacteria A.A. Inhibit. etc., 1945 March; 2 items
    - Penicillin I - Coli - chem. Induct. coli-4, 1946 January
  - 3 spiral notebooks by others, 1946-1947, undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - notes - Dolly von Hacht - Yale, 1946
    - Anne Flynn, 1947
    - D.J.R.- crosses for quadruple, [undated]
  - Lyophil - multiple stocks (Stanford, miscellaneous, Yale mutants), [undated] (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Lyophil cultures (Old Stanford, Yale, circa 1948? (Box 48, Folder 2)
    master books - other data of this date (also mutant descriptions).
  - Lyophil - Neurospora (Beadle and Tatum; Yale; Stanford; RU; miscellaneous), [undated] (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Mutant index cultures (includes Neurospora mutants), 1947 1949 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Vitamin stock cultures, 1947 1950 1956 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Folic + Fac II (Laura Garnjobst notes), 1947 February 1947 September-November (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Shikimic acid, 1947 1949 1950 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    Includes some laboratory notes and primarily correspondence dealing with testing of various compounds for the role of shikimic acid in Neurospora. Includes 1947 report by S.E. Reaume to Nutrition Foundation.
  - [nd] CD experiments etc. (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1947 1948 1951 1952 1954 1955 1962 1965 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    Includes Neurospora; SFO and Pab controversary and 1947 correspondence with S. Emerson concerning folicless mutant with copy of Emerson and Emerson ms.
  - 2492 - Warburgs, 1949 1950 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Y2492 - Acetateless mutants, 1949-1951 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous UE mat. s, 1949 1950 1951 1955 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Y7655 multiple mutants - Laura Garnjobst results, 1950 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Mannitol, 1951 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Yellow mutants data and experiments, 1950 1954 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Ergosterol etc MI, II, III; CI, II, III, IV, 1950 1951 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Glyceral mutant Y16762, 1951 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Degr. dimebutyrold CÂ¹â´, 1951 1952 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - R.C. Fuller (Stanford) bound notebook, 1952 January (Box 48, Folder 19)
    Includes some Tatum calculations.
  - M-IV Me x Ac to 2492 w. + culture, mannitol, inositol, 1953 May (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Key relating mutant name to mutant symbol; key relating isolation number to locus designation, 1953 October (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - PCA III experiments, 1954 October 1954 December (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - PCA G 1 and 6, 1954-1955 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Photoglynamic killing experiments, 1955 May 1955 July (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - S.L. Seki data for Seki ms, 1955-1957 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Synthetic crossing medium etc, 1956 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Graphs - N. coli etc. (Stanford), circa 1956? (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - R 2499 crosses, 1956 1965 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - S4355 crosses, 1956-1957 1960 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Compounds effecting Neurospora morphology and growth, 1957 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Nutrients, 1958 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Genetics (crosses), 1958 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - B 132, 1958-1964; 5 folders (Box 49)
    - B 132 Air-gas effects, 1958 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - B 132 + 3 growth data - tube and flask, 1958-1959 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - B 132 - old miscellaneous, 1959 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - B 132 Growth rate experiments, 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - B 132 Growth rate data: fatty acids etc., 1963-1964 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Sorbose experiments, 1958 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous experiments, 1957-1958 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Antiobiotics; u.v.-single cell mutation etc; divalent ions - morph; photosensit. screening; Nadi etc-screening; Iâ‚‚ treatment; temp. sens + and dying out; media; sorbose, so inositol; inos. phospho lipid.
  - Lenore's notes - Crosses and miscellaneous tests; media tests (morph plating), 1958-1959 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Barbara Crocken notes, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Sorbose cultures, 1957-1958 1965 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Crossing of mutants, 1961-1962 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - 89601 crosses to wt. R1006, 1959 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Inbred inos strains CDYCD, 1959 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Marker cultures x wt.- multi-stock, 1959-1960 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Ann Lafebreque and Mina Ristic notes: Summary book of mutants B, M,R, S, 1958 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Laura Garnjobst notes: Morphological mutants, 1958 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Isolation book, 1959-1966 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - N-Proteins etc, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Wild types N. crassa, 1960-1961 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Neurospora - Biotin, 1961 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Includes notes on 1961 RI summer project for biochemistry course.
  - Neurospora: cytology - ascospores, 1961 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Spring Indurated ascus, 1961-1962 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Bacterial ribosomes, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - RGL notebook, 1962-1963 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Mina Ristic notebooks (Box 52)
    Includes index in each book.
    - Book 1, 1961 April-1962 April (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Book 2, 1962 1963 1965 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Book 3, 1964-1965 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Mutants not located and/or dropped, 1961-1964 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Crisp book, 1962-1964 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Mutants R-2464 - R-2513; markers x w.t. 152 - 163; list of lyophilized cultures, 1962 1963 1964 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Testing of extracts, 1962 1963 1964 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - HET "Protos", 1962-1964 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Strains B5A; M-Sponge: R-2409 -R-2462, 1963-1964 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Crystals, 1963-1964 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    Includes only correspondence and photographs of crystals from J.F. Wilson to E.L. Tatum.
  - Crosses: R-3101. FøR; Second Føala resistant mutant run C, 1963-1964 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - AA analogues Part II; Føala resistance of Y7655a, arom-1; methods, 1963-1965 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Data on unsuccessful attempts to isolate sorbose-P from RC3-8A and Patch, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Merck "Sorbose" cultures in a notebook, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Sarah Reynolds notes: Misc; Tâ´; Linkage groups IV, VII, I, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Mina Ristic and Sarah Reynolds notes: Morphological mutants, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Ann Lafabreque notes: Ascospores cultures, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Barbara Crocken notes, 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Patch-sorbose-sorbitol, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Sorbose-sorbitol experiments, 1964 1967 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Mary Morgan notes: Miscellaneous experiments and results, 1965 1966 1967 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Linkage group V miscellaneous data, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 54, Folder 2-3)
  - Laura Garnjobst notes: abn notes, 1965 1966 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Distribution notes - morphs paper, 1966 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Linkage data notes, 1966-1967 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    [Editor's note: On June 10, 1976 to Archives by Anne Hammill].
  - P.R. Mahadavan notes: Relevant portions on information on Fraction I of cell wall, circa 1967 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Heterokaryons, 1967 1968 1969 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Growth rate data, 1970-1971 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Norite laboratory notes, 1973 February-October (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Anne Hammill notes, 4 folders (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous notes, circa 1967 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - 64, 67, 71, 74 Culture lines - "cross" notebook, 1962 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous records and summaries, 1968-1973 1975 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Prefixes, 1968-1971 1973 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Methods, undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
- 3x4 glass slides, 8; 6 boxes
  Where identified or dated so marked. Includes some duplicates. Also includes 2x2 lantern slides and boxes of samples and photo data.
  - ca. 90 3x4 glass slides. No identification (Box 56)
  - ca. 90 3x4 glass slides. No identification (Box 57)
  - ca. 90 3x4 glass slides (Box 58)
    - Unidentified
    - Subject identification
    - B55
    - B132
    - L929 S91
    - 1947
    - 5,000-10,000 (partial)
  - ca. 90 3x4 glass slides (Box 59)
    - 5,000-10,000 (continued)
    - 1959
    - 60,000's, 1960
    - 61,000's, 1961
    - 62,000's (partial), 1962
  - ca. 90 3x4 glass slides (Box 60)
    - 62,000's (continued), 1962
    - 63,000's, 1963
    - 64,000's, 1964
    - 65,000's (partial), 1965
  - ca. 30 3x4 glass slides (Box 61)
    - 65,000's (continued), 1965
    - 66,000's, 1966
    - 67,000's, 1967
  - 2x2 lantern slides. Most with some identification, 13 items (Box 61)
  - cardboard boxes of samples and photo data, 4 items (Box 61)
    - Box 1: [no year] samples. N. t + embedded paritheira - 6-7 day culture - methacylate, March 27
    - Box 2: N-tetrasperma. Photo data under ascospore cytochemistry, 1961 May 19
    - Box 3: samples. N. tetrasperma, Ii, perithecia, 1961 May 22
    - Box 4: samples. N. tetrosperma +; Perithecia (cut), 1961 May 22
    - [Box 61 partially filled]
- 5x7 scientific negatives, 1957-1967; 9; 2 boxes
  Some with prints.
  - 21 envelopes of 5x7 scientific negatives, 1957-1961 (Box 62)
  - 15 envelopes of 5x7 scientific negatives, 1961-1967 (Box 63)
- Film reels, 10; moving image
  Includes: NBC Continental Classroom.
  Conditions Governing Access
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media, due to the specialized equipment necessary to facilitate playback. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - Tatum "Biochemistry of heredity", 1960 May 25; moving image, 16 mm sound on film kinescope. (Reel 1)